yo I wonder if anyone's gonna show up it
is Easter alright alright alright now we
get people so you know it's uh this is
this the theme of this dopey Sunday is
safety maybe I should put my safety
goggles on it safety let's go be some
that no I actually bought these because
my eyes hurt from staring at computers
constantly so it's like flux for your
eyes scope II Sunday is back yeah um
because it's Easter you know so I bought
these actually because it's flux for
your eyes right oh it's able to lose
their - pretty crazy right I'll take
them off they look fun of the office no
but we actually was serious topic to
talk about today we're gonna talk with
safety
um so you know there were two uh two
crashes recently there was the uber
crash and the Tesla crash you know
sometime they like to call them
accidents and they are accidents but you
know crash is a more descriptive of what
actually happened um so first of all I
haven't really said anything about them
until now I wouldn't go that far
I'm sorry I wouldn't go far enough to
say that it wasn't
Uber's fault I think actually most of
the blame in the situation lies on the
safety driver remember guys there's no
such thing as level four self-driving
cars there are no self-driving cars that
can drive better than people some of
these driver assistance systems when
used in conjunction with the person nope
so open pilot is not anywhere near a
level four self-driving car and
everybody who uses it should know this I
question I question uh if you don't know
this I question a lot um so it was it oh
burrs fault I wouldn't blame the
engineers
Uber's fault invaded a vetting and
monitoring their safety drivers I would
say some of the blame lies there I would
say most of the blame lives with the
safety driver themselves not looking at
the road and you know the person I mean
don't blame the victim but she wasn't
being very careful so what's the take
away what's the take away so who's also
a a Tesla crash if you guys saw the test
the crash that hit the the concrete
barrier model acts totally burnt out in
the front so Tesla released a blog post
and then a follow-up blog post turns out
the car was on autopilot and there was
no hardly anyone could get there open
pilot working with their cars to come a
wholly fine I mean to be honest so when
you look at Tesla's statistics they're
they're pretty fair I mean look to think
that you're gonna have a system that
prevents all accidents is ridiculous the
goal is to make things safer and you
know Tesla obviously interprets the
statistics in a favorable light but I
don't think they're very far off from
the truth
uber statistics on the other hand do not
look good
we have a fatality on the roads I
believe Tesla said every eighty eight
million miles will usually go with the
number about one in every hundred
million and yeah Ober had only driven a
couple million miles so that was that
was probably far too soon there was an
interesting article that came
a computer segment of no I know no I
where you guys post the memes and I lead
them um this is an interesting article
former uber backup driver we saw this
coming I mean it's it's a clickbait but
um it actually the most interesting
thing I found in this article was yeah
you know this was one of our biggest
rules no phone in the left seat you know
we'll get to after we'll get to we get
to shit-talking Scobie Sunday in a bit
um so look at this so far roughly a
dozen operators have been fired for
using cell phones on their job and they
absolutely should be they absolutely
should be honestly if I was in if I was
Anna nuber and the uber driver was using
their cell phone in a way that I thought
was kind of unsafe like looking down for
five seconds I can say something I would
certainly give them a bad rating so yeah
guys don't don't use your phone and you
drive but the bigger problem is maybe
this when you guys drive with open pilot
one of the things that I think makes
open pilot a bit a bit safer than the
uber thing is you guys aren't driving
for 12 hours straight knowing these
people who were probably pissed an hour
early and they probably drive constantly
for 12 hours or eight hours or whatever
you get tired um but I do think that the
way forward for the space is driver
monitoring so if we look super cruise
has great driver monitor
I should have my links already
so maybe they show yeah so right here
I'm sorry I tried out supercruise on
Sunday I was very impressed they have it
they have a camera monitoring the driver
it felt very unlikely to make mistakes
which in some ways is bad because it
reassures you but in another way they
are they are monitoring you so I do
think that's the either way forward um
so this is my draft medium post that
I've been working on safety and driver
attention this is an interesting link
let's take a look to the left is the
original video in the middle is a
detergent glanced and action last
classification on the lots of images to
the Neal Network and then then you'll
know what produces on the Euler network
so happy Easter yes we're gonna start
doing similar sort of stuff so here we
can see yeah this was pretty good so
here's me in the for infusion um yeah
that's the uber video yeah um so this is
recorded with the front camera of Annie
on now this is recorded with the front
camera of a right-side up beyond I
deleted the one I recorded with the
upside down beyond but if you guys have
seen this is the way forward for iOS
come with the next release we're gonna
ask you to flip the top and the bottom
pieces we're also gonna start to offer
optional front camera recording and
uploading um so the the front camera
upload and record will be optional uh
when we do ship driver monitoring stuff
it will be mandatory um now I still
think we're in a were in a pretty ok
situation because you know open pilot
still makes a decent numbers
and as long as it does make mistakes you
won't confuse it for a superhuman system
also I hope nobody is driving 10 hours a
day you feel so sorry for the safety
driver I mean again if we had to if we
had to you know put blame you can also
break a lot of safety down into into
three categories right um so with a lot
of car companies talk about safety not
not all of them you have legal safety
which which which legal safety is very
concerned with okay who's to blame here
you know how do we how do we make sure
we stop down on this behavior that's
somewhat of an okay problem um then
there's signaling safety signaling
safety is to me absolutely disgusting
when you see you know oh my god like the
way they they write up these like you're
not helping the problem you're just
trying to virtually signal and I think a
lot of problems in the world are caused
by very sickly um but what we care about
is is is statistical safety right so we
now have hundreds of people out there
driving with all the pilot and we want
to figure out how to not just make open
pilot you know as safe as you doing but
how do we how do we move forward toward
making it safer right so open pilot is
always watching the road and then with
you always watching the road the most
cars in the road have at most one and
you know sometimes a little bit less
than one may be the expected value for
most cars in the road of a driver paying
attention is like 0.98 honestly if you
look at that situation if there was no
uber or anything criminally charged a
driver
you get their phone they tell somebody
maybe you do oh yeah you know I'm not
really interested in in who's to blame
I'm interested in how the industry moves
forward so who's that
uber
but yeah so we'll be releasing in two
weeks we'll be releasing the front
camera recording option and the
instructions to flip around your so as
you can see we haven't uh no I'm I'm not
interested that's the concept of legal
safety right like I'm not been
interested in determining the truth I'm
interested in getting the facts that's
why I didn't really say anything about
this you know everyone who said things
about this especially before the before
the the dashcam footage came out but
yeah so no actually so this is the
difference between organizations like
NTSB initiative right initiative
turbines like who has to pay and who's
to blame and what the but then a
organizations like NTSB who look like
they're really just trying to get to the
truth of the matter um so interesti
report on autopilot blasts if you
remember it they went into oh yeah you
like my big mouse pad big mouse pad
right I bought it before PewDiePie was
on the big mouse pad thing - how does it
handle running both cameras at the same
time both cameras have been running the
same time the whole time we run the
front camera the whole time we don't
upload it we don't record it but it's
been running so I would worry about that
we used it we used to use it for that a
rear view mirror thing which which
pretty much no one uses anymore but um
yeah so you'll be able to record both
cameras at the same time we're gonna
make it so you'll be able to access all
your front count and we haven't been
monitoring you don't worry we got our
first front camera footage today from
Annie on and one of our yachts no we
don't record the front camera we don't
record the microphone now we're gonna
have optional front camera recording but
it's gonna be off by default I'll begin
like I said if we do ship yeah bro III
know I don't wanna know you doing the
front seat like that's I don't really
want this video though but I think it is
a good step for safety could I display
the back of camera on you and you can
display the back of camera
um yeah facebooking back right right I
certainly don't want the mic I don't
even want to do optional microphone to
be honest guys I just I don't want that
data right you know that's certainly not
not a safety thing
the front camera I think it's the way
forward I think it is the way forward
you know Tesla shipped they called the
selfie cam in the model three so that's
kind of my take on these things I think
both of the recent accidents and that of
course the auto pilot truck accident in
Florida the auto pilot death in China I
think all four of those how much meth am
I on I think all four of those would
have been prevented if the driver was
paying attention
the new model doesn't use the blockchain
I have a left rolling okay this is
serious sculpey Sunday no oh oh you have
a giant panda if you have a giant panda
and you put that in the Neo I'll take
that back and you can I'll leave you the
discount me I'm sure you want audio to
catch other side admitting fault focus
focus so not interesting you guys what's
interesting is like just how can we how
can we improve statistical safety period
right anybody who's actually right you
know I think the computer security
industry is particularly like despicable
when it comes to a lot of this yeah well
not just drivers should pay attention it
you actually have a this this this may
be the word is uncanny valley for glad
to see you and yo we've kept I cannot
safety a lot right I just don't like
those safety is at the heart of
everything we do
what's that even mean like what you're
doing there is you're emotionally
signaling right please show me if you
care about safety please show me the
facts which test the crash so yeah I
mean Tesla has also gone billions of
miles with autopilot so to say there
have been three deaths that we know
about maybe some that we don't but still
the numbers I'm sure and far from what
you would expect
mandatory upload no no so mandatory
upload there's no mandatory upload for
the front camera I really I don't want
pictures your face if you would like to
share that we would certainly appreciate
it and will reward you with common
points but which facts but much
different discussion than ASCO P Sunday
should use this is a higher brow version
of shit-talking our competitors right um
yeah we can go somebody died with
autobot well again uh a week ago someone
died in it in a car crash to say that
like it was autopilot I mean autopilot
was on but we don't know again not maybe
I'm talking too soon about both of these
right you you still you have no idea
what what really happened all right bro
you're banned but yeah um do I know
Jimmy Jimmy so I don't know who that is
it's not like one of those things you
say like I want to see you pee or
something are you gonna buy a CD six
unfortunately we're not they're
expensive great pandas are a great pen
if you order the gray panda I'm sure
it'll ship Monday um if you if they're
out of stock then you gotta get a
getting quick when they go when they get
in I don't have facebook what I mean
yeah no I Drive the car right like
oh my god I don't care of course I care
about about safety it's like you you
have to there's no point in signaling
right and this is not you know this is
not signaling him I'm here to talk
honestly about a change that we're gonna
make to our to our open source a
self-driving car you know why we're
asking you guys to to flip the Aeons
over and anything else so maybe we'll
start a we'll start a slack channel
maybe we'll add a channel to the main
slack hash tag safety
and it's really a constructive
discussion about how we can move safety
forward yes we do keep stats on that
I mean people recover people touch very
quickly after after the awareness limit
I don't think there's like hitting the
limit is not necessarily bad I'm getting
special open pilot update for grey panda
users so that's coming but no this this
this sprint so we work in two-week
sprints this sprint we're really gonna
focus on
all right the things that we have on the
board are safety was there ever a crash
with open pilot um not that I know about
was there ever a crash wall open pilot
was engaged not to know about there was
there have been a few crashes in cars
with eons that we know about while the
system was off and the main one thing
was actually talked about on slack as
there was a rear ending if someone was
rear-ended it may be 10 miles an hour
not fast yeah it's interesting to you
know view that in in Cabana
well front-facing camera impact the
awareness limit so yeah I mean this is
kind of the replacement for the
awareness limit going forward so what
we're going to ship in the next release
is just front camera recording not front
camera monitoring yet interested in a
research paper on self driving unsafe
driving behavior maybe so again you know
we don't we don't even sell anything
that drives your car we give away some
free software we trust that the people
who here's the thing here's a here's
another thing where we're you know these
are my personal feelings on a company
and consumers we trust that you're smart
we trust that you guys the users have
open pilot you know aren't out there
doing stupid things now when you have
you have us so when you have Tesla this
is generally true you know you have a
certain sort of consumer who's probably
more more educated on this kind of stuff
when you if you want to reach millions
and millions of people
you've got to uh got to make it more
idiot-proof right oh the EON is a
dashcam the EON is absolutely a dashcam
it's old it's a trashcan like it really
is it really is a dashcam you know we do
make dash cams do we make a chipper app
we give away some free software called
open pilot um it does run on the EON do
you think factory sensors have fast
enough response or self-driving I think
almost every sensor is gonna have a
faster response in humans talk about
Aeon flipping
so the reason we flipped the Aeon is
because it puts the camera where it can
see the driver it puts the the front
camera where it can see the driver
what would classify as a non aware
driver a driver not looking at the road
you can see check out the MIT thing we
don't know yet so I suspect that okay
okay
okay some people just need to be blocked
bam bam we got a BAM people men
telescope show you better I thought I
loved batting people you know there's a
good there's a good eliezer yudkowsky
thing which talks about communities that
don't oh my god there's a good eliezer
yudkowsky blog post where he talks about
communities that don't ban people oh my
god oh good I lose some gun in the
Internet come on come on come on bro you
know I'm sharing my location on
periscope let's go um chat going crazy
today yeah oh yeah so we're gonna build
our own machine learning driver
awareness monitor from those people who
are nice enough to volunteer their
front-facing cameras
freaks on the internet guys but you know
what for the most part the Internet's a
lovely place you know positivity 105
scope is safety safety sculpey sunday um
sunglasses are show off the safety
sunglasses
I didn't actually get these for safety
it's like flux for your eyes yeah makes
my eyes feel a bit better will volunteer
thank you very much
um yeah we'll be recording on our
cameras we'll be recording on our cars
as well so I think kind of the way to
move forward and I think it'll be pretty
standard here's the thing - ah the only
one here today guys it's Sunday
he saw that autopilot worked without
lines oh how it works without lines kind
of I think works very similar to has a
Khmer I consider doing a security token
offering when there's a regulatory
framework for security tokens perhaps
well a smiley face balloon considered
eyes on the road absolutely not
front facing camera required for girls
for a minute no it's unrelated to the
Goldstar minute program the goldstream
minute program is just whether we can
make an app for your data from your data
so we will give point 5 camera comma
points per minute
for each person in a if I'm facing
camera what does the industry need to
focus on it under make something better
so you guys see here I'll show you what
I was working on and working on depth
we have much better depth nuts than this
but this one was chained unsupervised
just kind of cool so we can look at the
image down here and we just hide I'm
totally doing self-driving for winning
hey I'm not opposed to saving lives guys
but I'm doing it to win I'm not gonna
virtue signal and say anything else what
would I do is head of uber self-driving
think I'm doing here
I don't know I'd probably fire a lot of
people I think uber has a lot more
tolerance or than I do
everything torrents guys
whatever the problems to solve winning
is good keep winning I like winning no I
don't think that you have to go there
I'm sure that's that's like Chris our
instance take on it Chris Urmson steak
after somebody fell asleep in the Google
car was that there's no way to ever do
safe anything except for full autonomy
let agree with that conclusion but I do
think that you do need to monitor the
driver I had always kind of thought that
the current level of systems wouldn't
require driver monitoring because they
just aren't that good but better to
start now it's better to start now on
this kind of stuff who's the most
underrated autonomous car company zooks
will gray panda follow road track
smoothly without a base station so no
you can't using GPS alone you can't
localize accurately enough to follow a
track whose fan of AI isn't that the one
that like rear-ended somebody no the one
that we ran did somebody with the
reporter in their car if nobody gets
hurt it's still funny guys it's only not
funny when people get hurt what's comma
missing to take them to the yeah it does
fanime I
that was great it's not funny if someone
get hurt but if Noah gets hurt
this is no permanent consequences is
funny Oh Otto axe know what they're up
to
they're you know the guy's a computer
vision expert the car got all the poor
car yeah that's it's still funny it's
still funny if the car gets here all
cameras yeah they're all cameras I don't
know what their execution strategy is
you know they came out kind of a year
after us where you place it exactly
doesn't matter that much drafted AI is
way overrated I forget it but you know I
think the company's practically my best
camera just just their their rhetoric in
their blog posts they raised this overly
inflated there is 50 million dollars
right that's not a good thing um so we
raised money recently we haven't
announced how much or what valuation or
anything like that but I will say this
it's a lot less than 50 million dollars
because we're gonna do 50 million
dollars I don't need that right like you
shouldn't need that unless you've
ballooned your company to some inflated
size until of course you're a company
that's making you know tens of millions
in revenue we're not making tens of
millions in revenue yet
how does comma fit petal fit into safety
plans the coma petal is totally not a
product that's totally just for people
to mess with you know be aware that if
you're using a comma petal the absolute
worst-case is unintended acceleration
where you can step on the brakes put the
car in neutral but that's pretty
unlikely to happen what's a lot more
likely to happen is your car will lose
acceleration well either lose full
acceleration go to limp mode or lose
acceleration entirely that's QM in the
new auto industry yeah I'm surprised all
your people are here so that's
considered QM so you know you don't
really have to worry about that me
safety perspective that's just like you
know yeah you want to work I know come
she's never coming out guys I don't know
I don't know who's trolling with comma
steer I mean a lot of if you guys read
you know since we are talking about
safety
we'll go through the document that ships
with open pilot if you guys haven't read
it
chips the Dalton pilot called safety so
[Music]
basically our guys eat the effects of
super dangerous don't do them um you
have to two requirements in order to
make our system safe the driver must
always be capable to immediately retake
manual control of the vehicle by either
stepping on the pedal or pressing the
cancel button now this assumes of course
the drivers paying attention but yeah
the driver must always be capable we
could phrase that better
why was climate change the vehicle must
have altered the trajectory too quickly
to safely react meaning that's where you
get into torque limits so we limit the
gas to brake and the accelerator the EPS
mods you know there's a reason we don't
release them they are they have the
potential to be extremely dangerous so
with a bad EPS mod what you could
theoretically do is you could give
you're trying to steer the car the motor
is a lot stronger don't mess with EPS
plants guys unless you really know what
you're doing if you really know what
you're doing and I hope that whoever
figures out the EPS month doesn't
release a three step guide to EPS modern
right
so yeah the danger of EPS mods is that
motor has you don't need full turning
you don't eventually eventually maybe
but there's a lot that needs to be done
before them that's why we haven't
released that kind of stuff yet this
much easier ways to get full turning
besides EPS pods guys though no I don't
go to comic-con
I'm not I'm not a very deke guy like I'm
just not that i don't like cosplay anime
but yeah the yeah the property PS mods
is the motor in the car has more
stronger than you are so it can turn the
wheel
regardless of what you want to do so
that's why it's a little bit a little
bit dangerous whereas your braking is is
is is is always kind of considered to
safe action yeah at least it's strong
enough it is strong enough what
alternatives to EPS but I'm not gonna
I'm gonna tell you guys you know you saw
us driving the Prius around that wasn't
an EPS boy oh but there are ways to do
it
there are ways to do it and if you if
you figure them out then I you know
you've earned all kind of a you know I
believe if you if you're smart enough to
figure it out I believe you're smart
enough to be safe with it because I
believe you're smart enough to
understand the real dangerous any path
what does Tesla use flex right no I
don't think so
these Ethernet I think there's a lot of
their cars connected with like hundred
megabit Ethernet legit put an electric
that's what X Maddux doing right wheel
brakes for turning guys have you know
you know now okay see here's the thing
about EPS models the honda torque is
extremely low even probably for xing the
honda torque you would still be lower
than Tesla's torque and you'd be kind of
on par with Toyotas torque so there
probably could be quite a bit more
torque and have the system still be safe
now unfortunately they didn't allow this
by default so if you are super super
careful with mods and you know then you
make them on it's your car I'm not like
trying to stop you I'm just not gonna
help you right that's my it's my
prerogative as a free individual in
society right um but we have two other
things on the board
she do Berliner have detected the
pedestrian hit the brakes see the
problem with talking about that is
you're only looking at the one situation
where it didn't you don't even know kind
of what the success rates were until and
you know at least have a Tesla for
releasing the blog posts the blog posts
show something to the company I think
ubers released absolutely nothing on the
crash which this is bad PR perspective
really state family okay but doesn't
give me any information I mean I don't
even know whether that's true or not
anybody can write those words whether
they believe it or not you give me
information Wow
let's see that's that's that's you know
something I think I'm JSP yelled at
Tesla but Stewart things on the board of
the two more things on the board are
Amazon and ship plus and Amazon means
pandas will be going to Amazon and
shipper plus means shipper plus will be
made good we have to do a religious
checkup losses but it's been far too
long I want to let you guys know like
when I do releases anymore I know you
know we did the last release new all
complete more release ever no that's not
- you're gonna do we're gonna do 0.4 0.4
as a release why three commas on the
board well because you know how long
before worth a billion dollars right our
valuation is not a billion dollars yet
almost maybe maybe it's closer than it
was four three two is good good I'm glad
you like it
pandas do have SKU yes we bought
official SK use I don't know why jump
disapproves of Amazon Manas that's
between Trump and Amazon I have food I
like Amazon you know I like that was on
you know I find though there's a lot of
companies out there I don't like but
it's cheap it's good I don't know you
know I don't know anything else to
discuss on safety scope II Sunday
do I like Zuk Zuk sis incredible comic
relief yeah Nvidia self-driving yeah I
like Nvidia which company do I hate the
most
the Kinect I hate anybody who gotta take
themselves too seriously you know and
people have bad technology if you both
take yourself too seriously and have bad
technology I really don't like you if
you take yourself too seriously if you
have good technology it's forgivable if
you don't take yourself that seriously
and you don't have great technology
that's forgivable - OH
Desalle around terms yeah absolutely
once we have maps will we do you sell
our on turns and I know we show the
alert too much we can we can do better
you need to be am i chilling fun I'm
pretty hardcore guys I'm pretty intense
well I sell in European Amazon totally
not that sounds hard
what about using an existing EPS system
in a different car I wouldn't do that
open tanda you in the case are you guys
working on a board - you know if you do
it you do it I'm not I'm not opposed you
know you guys know my feeling I know
actual property I'm not gonna send you
the board file but if someone remakes it
uses the firmware like I know the case
yeah good you know the case is not the
kids ain't a big secret you could take
our case off and use that using 3d
printer the case is a big secret on the
e all now not open e on what else it's
gonna look at me PS flash guys but theme
over the next two weeks is safety so I
mean if you're the French website yeah I
don't know if someone wants to buy me a
Pew Joe I will still not support it cuz
I don't have time I already told ya go
good it was just
I got rice krispie treat plan yeah yo
you guys know I've come around a lot on
mobile hi and mobilized blog post where
they released
tactic new pedestrian that was your
savage that was your savage like when I
saw that I just couldn't believe mobile
I did that
pure savage props to Omashu uh-huh yeah
boo boo drivers EPS mods increase save
do you know they don't pay attention 1k
for for giraffe but you mean like a
bounty or you're willing to pay me a
thousand dollars were for giraffe
what about Yolo what just like like as a
life motto that's like or like Yolo net
yoga meeting meeting rice crispy lamb
we're gone
alright I'll put it up on the store
shipping time four to twelve weeks
Yolo self-driving Yolo net it's I think
that the idea of like detecting a type
of object is dumb I think that the right
solution is you want to whitelist not
blacklist right you should never listen
to the thing is that you will not hit
you should have a list of places you can
drive this is known as like free space
detection I think free space detection
is a much better idea than like trying
to class up identify and classify a
pedestrian right um
just do it so someone to learn I I if
you ask my TTA nephew Eric it's
somewhere in between February and March
you don't know your money but you
Shepherd alright alright um well Neil
continue to work yeah I mean I'm not
gonna like I can't reach into your neo
and break it you guys know we are
offering a neo to egon upgrade $400 and
sending your neo and we will get you a
brand new like new phone one plus three
T 64 gigabyte eon
when will ship with cash in the box you
can't send cash in the mail bros the
drug dealers made that illegal
you used to be able to sing cash in the
mail but then that drug dealers messed
it up for everybody
[Laughter]
don't you need pedestrian detected to
predict their behavior yes maybe but
that should be in a do you not really
know you actually need to detect the
evolution of free space over time
oh is the DSP only unlocking with the
Aeon bootloader maybe
oh yeah the DSP oh free the DSP calm
guys how do you keep focused when coding
so like I sit in cold for like 12 hours
I wake up in the morning I code for a
couple hours I should talk for a couple
hours and sometime I caught a night
multi vehicle convoy mode stupid
I do like Mountain Dale I'm one of those
guys called red man
Code Red Mountain do they know they know
their target audience no that shit's for
me favorite Twitter accounts who do I
like oh you know they've been blowing up
lately like like um neva and that whole
crowd you got like the guy with the with
that with the half face I follow a bunch
and you see you my favorite Twitter
accounts of the people I follow you know
people who are interested in truth I'm
interested in truth I love truth guys
model predictive control even even if he
hates me man he's awesome that I'll
always think that even if you all let me
buy one of his cars I forget there was
something I was gonna respond to there
but yeah my dad's an OG right but that's
pretty cool what do you think I learned
this from guys but you know ma'am
adjust following distance know what's up
with the comma sign on your hoodie bro
we're calm a I know we're high we are
calm a I check us out comedy I we make
open-source self-driving cars our slogan
is ghost riding for the masses
can you come visit common HQ no you
can't no we don't do we don't do visits
but you can watch on periscope where can
you go to PewDiePie's apartment no won't
the car be unable to stop for a waiting
pedestrian well yeah but there's there's
other ways to track it right like you
can track the evolution of free space
over time yeah of course we can hold the
address I'm not gonna give you a tour
like you could just show up here and
we'll be like no no door and close the
door and you'll be like why did I come
here has anybody got a comma tattoo yet
not that I know I don't have any tattoos
oh man yeah we got our cream of dads uh
he's got he's got a nice on man I can't
use his wheel speed sensors maybe I can
run my dad sniffer plus I do you want to
be interviewed in your radio show in
Minnesota yeah if you send a so viv viv
VI V at comedy I reach out and yeah if
it's easy we'll do it am I gonna do
another cross-country tour absolutely
the self-driving car awareness tours
every year bro you know the three commas
in Silicon Valley yeah yeah yeah of
course the free space would not be
affected by a pedestrian waiting a
sidewalk no not the free space at the
time but a prediction of future free
space would which is probably the space
you want to operate and you want to
operate in pixels and not objects yeah
what up dad random but how old are you
how old you think
yeah my family's back in in New Jersey
I'm here in the coma mansion am i famous
I used to be famous guys I didn't want
to be famous sauce a scam I'm 28 I'm 28
now you really don't to be famous I
think that was the last time like the
periscope went on too long because I was
bored I started really telling you guys
about like yeah I'm 28 I'm 28 I'm 28 how
does factory Toyota pedestrian detection
work not well what was it like when Sony
sued you yeah yeah come at me bro you're
27 didn't do with your life well
you know today's the first day of the
rest of your life go do right what
can I say thank you
today is the first day of the rest of
your life that was a line from clerks
too which was an incredibly sad movie
like clerks was okay have young guys
work in a convenience store clerks too
is about like some 30 year old to work
at a fast food joint that's sad
operating pixels not objects is that a
clue no radar can operate in pixels as
well so what I mean by pixels is like
area delimited not object too limited um
the objects are all done later on in the
radar so you can certainly you know you
just what do you want talk to you listen
to him talk about Oh Gracie I've found
the golden egg man um you can radar
cameras are the same thing kind of I
mean Raiders are a midden they emit
but like you can still just talk about
them as like they're fundamentally you
know just listening on frequency right
and that's what the cameras doing as
well but a camera is passive and not
active oh wow bidding light up guys I
really will put that up if someone wants
to pay $1000 for for giraffe we'll build
it it'll shift in four weeks uh yeah
we're summer entrance um gold star
portal soon - and soon
yes summer interns give me a job at come
AI what I ever join the army for free
med school I have absolutely no interest
in going to med school I'm a little bit
more interested in joining the army to
be honest if I could go for like a six
month basic training I would volunteer
I don't really want to be deployed but
um if they could put me through basic
training and basically if somebody comes
to invade America I'm called up only if
someone calls to invade I'm not going
over there I'm not fighting anybody over
there but they come here if somebody
comes here to America you know them down
to fight hacker are you gonna hack it
I'm an X hacker I'm retired
just like Julian Assange I shouldn't say
things like that you're scared of being
deployed - yeah I wouldn't want to be
deployed uh in the army
we should talk about oh yeah that won't
you talk about let's go bro let's go
let's talk about working together let's
go hi thank you for coming on periscope
by the way that's this is the way that
we can interact with companies anyone
who sends me an email the Deaf doll man
yup I'm thinking about it yeah you know
I'm not sure what the Army's like today
but I support the idea of like an
organization like that I'm building
those skills thank you for being here
you're welcome
yep I don't think I'm actually gonna
join the army but there was something I
considered at one point my life my
mother told me I can't though what am i
eating I'm eating rice krispies treat
lamb my mom said it's me X hacker I'm an
X hacker but okay so let's hear about
this plan for working together with an
electric car company any chance we'd
open another office location absolutely
not no I didn't try again to buy a Tesla
by one they don't want me to buy one I
mean I'll respect that you know I got a
respect respect for someone I didn't
know you know it's just cuz I respect
Tesla's because I respect Elon with
someone I didn't respect I get your car
but you can't stop me basically using
all the Tesla patents for the drivetrain
now no no no no so so here's what I'm
saying how far you along how many
how many cars do you have well yeah how
many have you built that's that's that's
the real question right your five
prototypes okay and then what's your
what's your ramp up plan when do you
plan to when do you plan to ship cars to
consumers okay but when do you plan to
ship cars to consumers okay so you're
past the prototype phase only for a
ride-sharing no consumers okay I mean
but when do you plan to like scale up
production and then if you're only using
it for ride-sharing I mean okay um so
what I would say is here's how we can
work together if you want
cama AI to write a port for your car
it's one hundred fifty two hundred fifty
thousand dollars and bring us a car
and put two hundred fifty thousand
dollars in escrow will write a port for
open pilot and then that port will work
similarly to other to the other cars in
the open pilot fleet and you'll be able
to buy Aeons and you'll be able to
install them in the car so yeah
basically what we can offer to aspiring
car manufacturers is a 250 K port
package will port it and we'll push it
in the open source code or I'll compile
it will push an open source version will
push basically a branch that works on
your car
$250,000 now if you're thinking about
making cars $250,000 shouldn't really be
a consideration to you has anyone in
Australia engaged open palette yes we
were few Australian users yeah no I mean
look it's 200 decays really incredibly
cheap um so we don't basically we don't
do meetings we don't do we have so many
meetings where nothing happens um that's
my deal when you're ready to move
forward with let's say a $50,000 down
payment and a car then we'll invite you
to the office to go over any any
specifics you know you show up with the
car you show up with a $50,000 check you
pay us the balance when we do the port
we push it open source the truth is most
meetings just go absolutely nowhere
I'm so once you're ready to work with us
like that we're happy to do it but you
know yeah it's basically you know if you
want more if you want to know what
you're getting go out and buy a Honda
buy a neon try it out if you like it
then basically you will get that on your
car assuming it has assuming it has
actuators assuming it has some spec for
actuators that we can tap into so then
why are us the money why are the 50k
down payment we'll meet and bring the
car will do the port it should take us
about two months and then we can when
we're done the rest of 20 toward UK but
we don't really do meetings anymore
I found that most meetings go almost
nowhere Honda's actually do work a
little bit better than Toyota's that's
what I'm saying by Honda and the Civic
will be more representative of what
you're getting assuming that you have a
good spec for how to actually control
the stuff on your car if it does need
radar you need a forward-facing radar
right now um we can try to do vision
only but the quality is not going to be
as good but any any normal radar is is
good but I assume that's something
already shipping in your car I do it on
periscope
daddy you ready we gotta get those great
pandas back in stock um teasing new
model for Toyota that we're doing new
models it's coming it's coming it's
coming but ya know I mean there's
there's nothing that you know uh maybe
the next level will be will be will have
like a Skype conversation that we
periscope know if when I first started ,
we met with like everybody we had
meetings with all the car companies all
the tier ones okay you'll have the car
yeah yeah yeah I'm always down to talk
on slack so you'll have the car done by
November okay okay um so in November
once you have the car once you have the
50k down payment will sign a contract
you wire that down payment over bring
the car by will chat we'll go over any
specific details to your car if we can't
do it if for some reason we can't get
the port quality to match the Honda will
give you your car and the money back I
don't believe in being paid for a work I
didn't do well oh but yeah I mean you
know don't expect level for yourself to
having client stuff's not real cool ah
yeah a great job with the pedal right
that's not even his main job excellent
look at the successful look at the
successful periscope meetings can I tell
the test the story now yes sure um so
mune VF went to the Tesla dealership oh
it was such a great experience we were
sitting like a Model X with the moonroof
I was beautiful
I'm we're like okay we're gonna buy one
of these cars so we're like we get one
tomorrow um so we're at the dealership
we set a delivery date of tomorrow at I
think it was 11 a.m. I wake up in the
morning I'm super excited I'm getting a
Tesla today then I get a call from the
dealership at like 10 a.m. and they're
like you know we're sorry your orders
been canceled by the main office I think
that they want to reach out to you you
know let them know when you're available
so I'm like look I'm around all
this is all I'm doing today I'm getting
a Tesla and yeah then I got a call from
Tesla's head legal counsel at at 2 p.m.
and I was kind of like look man if
you're gonna like call me up with your
legal things I'm not gonna like I don't
know you know we didn't even get to the
point where he was asking for things
like I would never sign anything special
to buy a production car so you know I
was a little a little upset by that
but hey man you know let's do business
they're allowed to do that we banned
people from the periscope they bad
people I thought we were pros but if
we're not pros is cool too man I mean
they're not you know you can buy so if I
wasn't doing , what would I be driving
not a Tesla I used to have a
mercedes-benz or you don't get why they
did it uh you know they don't want I
mean he was notorious about this oh I
could certainly get one I could
certainly get one this isn't actually
stopping me from getting a Tesla but
like also I kind of wouldn't trust
buying a car from Tesla where they've
singled me out like that
you guys know they have SSH they have
root and Hall of cars I don't want to be
singled out if I did buy a Tesla by it
under my alter ego named not from a
Tesla dealership from from a third party
and yeah no one would ever know and guys
maybe I have a Tesla time just trolling
you all and keeping the the whole front
oh right yeah what would I be driving I
have Mercedes s-class they're nice there
were really nice cars
I wish the autonomy was better right
away it does look nice no way Aipom
cruise yeah that's a cruise without two
zeros sir do you have zeros in your name
that's right I have zeros of my name
cool and dr. James Dean the point star
Woody's in his name right not not the
guy who wrecked his portion died not bad
James Dean um I would ease all I rented
that a for you guys know I love that a
forever you know the problem without him
who knows
problem with Audi motorcycle autopilot
Nebu arey
yeah the post curated reverse-engineer
it or they're scared I come on periscope
talk about a bad autopilot the
seesaw winner that's right I didn't win
the seesaw those were the days
do I think Wei mo is getting any
significant market share they bought
20,000 overpriced Jaguar mobiles
I'd the stupid announcement like why
doesn't way mo use Toyota Priuses oh can
you reverse engineer a neural net well
not the weights themselves but you can
certainly look at the net architecture I
don't even have to reverse engineer it I
can just read there's public stuff on
the Tesla motor forums where somebody
always does it for me so I just read
periscope I just read I test the motor
forms sorry I read the words and
sometime the words get caught up in my
mind what happened to safety we talked
about safety and now it's talking
to our do i still play playstation i
never play playstation no i mean it's
like it's not that i pace is bad right I
haven't been in an i pace
I hear it's kind of nice maybe but it's
just it's a poor choice like for example
why would you use an electric car like
you just have to deal with that now
which you didn't have to deal with
before with your Pacifica minivans right
later man
yeah the next step in south tribe and
that's more what I mean it was more that
the hype didn't match the reality yeah
and they bought twenty thousand of an
untested first year production car I
wouldn't do that like that's just a poor
business choice oh and then oh my god
are you guys want to bring up the video
oh it's it's so laughable but good bad
guys I bought some Kinect
I bought the dip and it didn't recover
and I was devastated I lost my house I
got to move out that's not funny some
people actually lost their house it's
still funny because nobody got hurt
[Music]
electric cars feel futuristic see that's
but I'm not about to feel
man all right so let's find the way and
let's go on way most Twitter and let's
look at this announcement and I just
can't
yeah I know nobody thinks about it that
way
all right you can probably the people of
waynebow who made this decision opinion
on uber what do you mean my opinion on
uber I don't know um I think they could
have been more careful
but you know maybe they were my opinion
uber hasn't really changed you guys know
that I was a fan of Travis kalanick the
new over is just it's just corporate
this one oh yes
or your best investment if Bruce
digital versus analog the steering the
brakes are the same in electric cars you
know red then this guy this guy so you
know I'm not with you guys some of you
might know the story when I met with
Jaguar Land Rover but like okay opinion
on Nutella negative opinion of watching
this current capability and innovative
advanced technology and you all know
that Land Rover invented the premium SUV
or check or the disc brake for cars both
brands have a long track record of
creating so let's pause the video and
let's talk for a second about the word
he used both brands have a track record
and that's how these car companies view
themselves and that's kind of what I
would like what I'm anti right I don't
want like what is this he hasn't said
anything Jaguar and Land Rover always
deliver
okay but like you haven't shown me any
fact that you improve that you've just
said those words
it's practically Trump esque the game
changes everyone is you know in the
automotive industry wants to create a
game-changer an icon everybody in the
game changer and icon what is that what
is that
of the truest roses the opportunity to
do so is very very rare
and now what's the I place the first
consequently designed and engineered
bacteria clean well away okay so the
first consequently electric designed
elect battery electric vehicle no that's
not true but then he actually follows it
up he actually follows it up with
something from a premium brand from a
premium brand what does that he's
speaking to his audience but like guides
us into smart sustainable mobility and
the pace dramatically guides us could we
just like visualize this for a minute
like like here's an eye base and like
we're all like walk-in behind the old
guys the eye pace is leading us yeah
he's like the Genghis Khan of electric
vehicles man he's like leading us into
battle grace space and cookies a product
for game changers creating unprecedented
ladies and gentlemen electrification the
technological prerequisite for
autonomous drive in the future
electrification is the technological
prerequisite for autonomous driving he
finally says something that's a fact and
it's not true that doesn't even make any
why that doesn't even make any sense
and be led and we have a clear vision of
smaug mobility enjoyable entertaining
and exciting Chinese giving our
customers procedures available time back
okay I'm I'm over this guy um but what
we should talk about is who has redeemed
from
self's um we're gonna we're gonna leave
off with where's the time like the time
used to be on periscope I think they got
rid of it so they wouldn't know how long
I've been doing this for we are gonna
talk about the biggest redemption of
2018 award we're gonna hand it out right
now biggest redemption of 2018 from who
got made fun of to who's not gonna be
made fun of anymore who you guys do you
think who do you think
no no super he's still gonna be made fun
of but not because of anything super who
did just because of like supers who do
you think 2018 it's the year of the No
oh it's been over now I really gotta go
I got things to do today Ford it's the
year of the Ford you guys got it it's
the other Ford guess what Ford has just
made all these features standard on the
2019 fusion which we love to see we
can't wait to support the 2019 fusion
you guys know we have a 2018 fusion I'm
gonna leave you with Ford is redeemed
there will be no more making fun of Ford
on these periscopes Ford has redeemed
themselves
congratulations round of applause
clapping with one hand for Ford Ford has
redeemed themselves
Ford's back up at the sticker I was not
happy about this bigger don't get me
started on this picker but Ford has
redeemed themselves so Ford is out of
the ship in Jaguar has moved themselves
further into the ship in IV this
standard on 2019 thank you scope ease
thank you for joining for this safety
scope II Sunday our next two weeks will
be focused on safety and we'll be
starting the safety channel on slack so
we can discuss safety constructive
positive things only absolutely no fear
mongering fear-mongering is never
tolerated make sure to click that like
and subscribe button and make sure to
bio your on shop comet day I gray
pandas will be back in stock next week
if you've been looking to buy a gray
panda Happy Easter
I don't think Ford on the Jaguar Happy
Easter do everybody and to all a good
night bye-bye